Guide to the Printmaker File [1730]-2014, undated (bulk 1800-1860) PR 58
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Prints 16 x 20" to 30 x 40"
  - Varian, George (1865-1923)
    - [Jeremiah Vanderbilt House, Flatbush Ave.], [1911] (Box Unknown container 923 for instance of [Jeremiah Vanderbilt House, Flatbush Ave.], Folder unknown container)
      Two copies, one a canceled plate
    - [Unidentified historic Brooklyn house], [1911] (Box Unknown container 924 for instance of [Unidentified historic Brooklyn house], Folder unknown container)
  - Wallace, William H.
    - Harlem River in 1870 (Box Unknown container 925 for instance of Harlem River in 1870, Folder unknown container)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (proof), 1882 (Box Unknown container 926 for instance of Middle Dutch Reform Church (proof), Folder unknown container)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (final), 1882 (Box Unknown container 927 for instance of Middle Dutch Reform Church (final), Folder unknown container)
    - [New York from Staten Island (?)], 1890 (Box Unknown container 928 for instance of [New York from Staten Island (?)], Folder unknown container)
    - [Post Office at Cedar and Nassau Streets], 1888 (Box Unknown container 929 for instance of [Post Office at Cedar and Nassau Streets], Folder unknown container)
    - [Prospect Park - Apple Trees], undated (Box Unknown container 930 for instance of [Prospect Park - Apple Trees], Folder unknown container)
  - Wallace, William H.
    - [Farmhouse], undated (Box Unknown container 931 for instance of [Farmhouse], Folder unknown container)
    - [Man fishing], undated (Box Unknown container 932 for instance of [Man fishing], Folder unknown container)
    - [Man on horseback in forest], undated (Box Unknown container 933 for instance of [Man on horseback in forest], Folder unknown container)
    - [Rabbit by stream], undated (Box Unknown container 934 for instance of [Rabbit by stream], Folder unknown container)
  - Welling, Richard (1926-2009)
    - From Brooklyn Bridge (164/200), 1976 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
    - Singer Building Demolition, 1967 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
    - Untitled [construction of World Trade Center?], undated (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
  - Werger, Art (b.1955)
    - Daybreak (56/75), 1997 (Box Unknown container 935 for instance of Daybreak (56/75), Folder unknown container)
  - Whitman, Karen (b. 1953)
    - Downtown (15/85), 2003 (Box Unknown container 936 for instance of Downtown (15/85), Folder unknown container)
  - Wilbur, Lawrence Nelson (1897-1988)
    - Manhattan Mountains, 1938 (Box Unknown container 937 for instance of Manhattan Mountains, Folder unknown container)
    - The Spire [Empire State Building] (4/100), undated (Box Unknown container 938 for instance of The Spire [Empire State Building] (4/100), Folder unknown container)
    - Under the Bridge (6/27), 1988 (Box Unknown container 939 for instance of Under the Bridge (6/27), Folder unknown container)
    - [Produce stands] (7/75), 1976 (Box Unknown container 940 for instance of [Produce stands] (7/75), Folder unknown container)
    - [Produce stands] (9/75), 1976 (Box Unknown container 941 for instance of [Produce stands] (9/75), Folder unknown container)
  - Wilson, James & Isaac Eddy
    - "Chronology Delineated to Illustrate the History of Monarchical Revolution", 1813 (Box Unknown container 942 for instance of "Chronology Delineated to Illustrate the History of Monarchical Revolution", Folder unknown container)
      published by Eddy, Vermont. Two copies, one colored, and another copy of the bottom half of the plate.
  - Unidentified artist
    - New York from Jersey shore by night, undated (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
- Series III: Prints larger than 30 x 40"
  Series III. Prints larger than 30 x 40" includes prints stored in frames and in oversize drawers.
  William Burgis' "A South Prospect of Ye Flourishing City of New York" is widely considered to be the most important early view of New York. The print was originally printed in London on four sheets of paper and published in 1719-1721. In 1746, the plates were changed somewhat and the print reissued by Thomas Bakewell. A copy of each of the states is included in this series. Additionally, Burgis' 1722 view of Boston can be found here.
  - Burgis, William (fl. 1716-1731)
    - "A South Prospect of Ye Flourishing City of New York in the Province of New York in America", ca. 1719-1721 (Box Framed - hanging on wall in 2NW, Folder unknown container)
      line engraving designed by Burgis, engraved by John Harris (fl. 1685-1739)
    - "A South Prospect of Ye Flourishing City of New York in the Province of New York in America", 1746 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Burgis)
      line engraving designed by Burgis, engraved by John Harris (fl. 1685-1739), printed and sold by Thomas Bakewell, London. State II.
    - "A South Prospect of Ye Great Town of Boston in New England in America", 1722 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Burgis)
      line engraving designed by Burgis, engraved by John Harris (fl. 1685-1739), printed and sold by William Price, Boston.
      See also: Series I.
  - Behnken, William (b. 1943)
    - Lightscapes (3/50), 2003 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder A-D)
  - Bury, Pol
    - [Guggenheim], undated (Box Oversize flat files, Folder A-D)
  - Eller, Evelyn (b. 1933)
    - "My New York", 1998 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Eller, Evelyn)
      Mixed media collage unique Artist Book
    - "Immigration", 1999 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Eller, Evelyn)
      Paper collage
  - Grooms, Red (b. 1937)
    - On Your Mark, Set, Go! (9/72), 2002 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - Ruckus Taxi, 1982 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - Subway (40/75), 1971 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
  - Haas, Richard (b. 1936)
    - Flatiron Building (11/60), 1973 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - Little Singer Building (36/40), 1971 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - Manhattan View, Governor's Island, 1999 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - George Washington Bridge (38/200), 1999 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Hass, Richard)
      aluminum print
    - Manhattan Bridge (65/200), 1999 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Hass, Richard)
  - Harris, Arthur John (b. 1959)
    - Flatiron (1/150) (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
  - Jacquette, Yvonne (b. 1934)
    - New York Harbor Composite, 2003 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder I-R)
  - McPherson, Craig (b. 1948)
    - FDR Drive, 1993 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder I-R)
  - Morper, Daniel (b. 1944)
    - "Metropolis" (26/100), 1989 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder I-R)
      etching with aquatint
  - Seltzer, Phyllis (b. 1928)
    - Intersection, 2001 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder [too large for folder - at bottom of drawer])
      heat transfer print
    - Time out (3/3), 2003 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
  - Werger, Art (b. 1955)
    - Attraction, 2003 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
  - Yewell, J. Floyd
    - George Washington Bridge (19/150), 1931 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
    - George Washington Bridge, 1931 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
    - Goethals Bridge (59/150), undated (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
  - Unidentified artist
    - "White Column Facade", 1999 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)